BHAVIK GILBERT

Software Engineer

- bhaviklob@hotmail.com
- → +447405805628
- **Bhavik Gilbert**
- Bhavik-Gilbert
- Portfolio Website

EDUCATION

Computer Science BSc (Hons)



King's College London

2021 - 2024

- Associate of King's College London
- · Professional Skills for a Globalised World

CS50 Online



Harvard University

2022

A-Levels

Mathematics, Computer Science Physics, Economics



Leyton VI Form College

2019 - 2021

SKILLS

- Pvthon
- 🎍 Java
- 🔋 👸 HTML/XML/CSS
- g Javascript
- PHP
- **G C**/C++
- Scala
- SQL

INTERESTS

- Volleyball
- Badminton
- Travel

AWARDS

- Forage JPMC & Co Software **Engineering Virtual Experience**
- Duke of Edinburgh Bronze & Silver
- OFQUAL Open Awards Entry 3 Award in Employability and Professional Development (RQF)
- OpenLearn Introduction to software development & Technological innovation: a resource-based view

REFERENCES

· edwin.nganga@leyton.ac.uk

PROFILE

Driven by my passion for Tech, I've pursued a range of experiences to expand my knowledge around it. As a result, I've dabbled in several fields including: data analysis, game development, machine learning, web development and database systems. Proceeding forward, I plan to continue developing my knowledge as a software developer, adapting alongside new technologies and design structures, further improving my problem-solving and algorithmic thinking.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Graduate Teaching Assistant



King's College London

September 2023 - Current

- Module: 5CCS2PEP Practical Experiences of Programming
- Taught C++ and Scala with their coding constructs, alongside guiding students through programming exercises.

Software Engineer Analyst Intern



JPMorgan Chase & co

June 2023 - August 2023

- Team Athena Market Data
- FullStack Developer | Python
- Worked on a codebase with over 50 million lines of code.

Location Camp Manager



Funtech

July 2022 - August 2022

- Managed and supported tutors across 7 on-site locations to cultivate a safe and encouraging environment for learning
- Provided technical/IT/teaching support across courses, maintaining safeguarding standards, liaising with tutors, talking to clients and troubleshooting issues of all natures
- 3D Game Development(Unreal Engine 4), CyberSecurity(Kali Linux), Python(Basic/OOP/Pygame Development/AIML), Touch Typing, Roblox Development, Minecraft(Mods/Redstone) Development, Lego Robotics, Java(Basic)

PROJECTS

Deafblind Social Media Application

JPMorgan Code For Good Hackathon, NGO: DeafBlind UK

Group Project - 5 Contributors

Python/SQL | Social Media Web App (Flask/ColorBlind/PIL/CV2/DeepFace)

- Social Media website where users can post text, images, blogs and events specially built for deafblind people
- Facial Recognition Login, Integrated Google Sign-in, Image Colour Daltonization, Alt Text, Text to Speech, Unlimited Image Magnification, Simple & Accessible UI/UX Design

Greggor Financial Companion

Group Project - 8 Contributors

Python/Javascript | Financial Tracker Web App (Django/PIL/Tabula/Pandas/Numpy)

- Financial tracker web application, enabling users to track expenditures across multiple banks, categories and currencies
- Incorporates a full suite of automated unit tests
- Features including: Getting Transactions from Bank Statement, Account Balance Projections (Based on Interest), Subscriptions and a Finacial Quiz

Phase Folding Kepler Exoplanet Luminosity

Python | Data Analysis & Graphical Manipulation (Pandas/Numpy/Matplotlib)

Calculating the radius and orbital period of an exoplanet from the change in luminosity of the star it's orbiting using phase folding.

Visit my portfolio website for more information